# 广西 柳州
Liuzhou, Guangxi
# 深夜里的豆浆油条
Soy milk and “Youtiao” (Chinese cruller) in the midnight
# 您好 阿姨这个叫什么
Hello auntie. What is this?
# 沙堆
Shadui
# 那两种叫什么
What are those two?
# 那个叫油堆
That is Youdui
# 站在那么远的地方
You still can smell soy milk
# 你都能够闻到豆浆的味道
Even from far away
# 真的很香
Smells really good
# 而且就是这种豆香 豆香
Especially the smell of yellow bean
# 醇香 醇香的香味
And aromatic-smelling
# 你拿着 你端着
You take and hold it
# 我端
I will hold it
# 哪边还有位置
Where can we find a seat?
# 里头
Inside
# 今天咱们来吃的是豆浆和油条
We will try soy milk and Youtiao today
# 这家店呢 是一家深夜豆浆油条馆
This is a late night soy milk and Youtiao restaurant
# 靠豆浆 油条 火爆起来
Famous for its soy milk and Youtiao
# 来的时候 咱也能发现
We can see
# 这边的过道就是厨房
The aisle here is the kitchen
# 几口大锅在里面炸各种各样的东西
And some woks are frying various foods inside
# 像油条 油堆这种油炸的东西
Like Youtiao and Youdui
# 这边豆浆有冰的 有热的
They have both iced and hot soy milk
# 包括这些油炸的东西
3 yuan for each
# 都是3块钱一份
Including these fried foods each are 3 yuan
# 我要说一点就是
What I wanna say is
# 它这个油条是刚炸出来的
These Youtiao are just fried
# 你看 外面金黄
You see the surface color is golden
# 但是里面 松软 而且有很多的孔隙
While the inside is soft and puffy
# 刚才夹的时候 你都能听到那种
You can hear the sounds of the crispness
# 窸窸脆脆的声音
When you clip it
# 就是光听声音
You will think it is very crispy
# 你就会觉得 很脆
by just listening to the sound
# 我这个是冰豆浆
This is iced soy milk
# 尝一下
Let me try it
# 醇香的甜豆浆
Mellow sweet soy milk
# 桌子和椅子都太矮了
The table and chairs are too short for me
# 我每次吃饭的时候 都得这么着
This is how I sit every time I eat
# 还有 你看 它这个豆浆像牛奶一样白
You see this soy milk as white as milk
# 但是喝起来 它是加了糖的
But there's sugar in it
# 所以说 会觉得很甜
So you will taste sweetness in the soy milk
# 咱们以前都是热豆浆配热油条
We used to have hot soy milk with hot Youtiao.
# 油条的表面很快就会松软下来
The surface of Youtiao will be soft soon
# 但是这个冰豆浆 或者说是凉豆浆
But this iced soy milk, or cold soy milk
# 配油条来说
Is good to go with Youtiao
# 还能够保持油条外面这种脆脆的口感
Because it still keeps the crispy texture
# 吃一口 咬下去 还是能够
You can taste the mellow flavor of soy milk
# 爆出豆浆的香醇味道
When you give a bite of Youtiao and milk
# 这边炸的东西除了油条之外 还有这种
Besides Youtiao, they also have other fried foods like this
# 这个是空心球剪碎的
This is cut from a hollow ball
# 剪成了三角形
Into triangles
# 这种是实心球剪碎的
This is cut from a solid ball
# 一看里面还有糯米饭 黏连的状态
There is sticky rice inside, very sticking
# 所以说呢 这边的炸货其实有很多种
So there is a variety of fried foods
# 都是来配豆浆的
All good to eat with soy milk
# 有没有发现 这是一桌甜蜜的体验呢
Look, what a sweet experience on our table
# 可能也正是因为这份甜蜜
So that’s why there are people who
# 所以说 很多深夜有故事的人
have their own stories are willing to eat it and try it
# 都愿来吃一吃 尝一尝
Because of those sweet experiences
# 其实我觉得食物是生活的一种点缀
Actually I think food is an embellishment to our life
# 很多人忙碌了一天 觉得很累
People feel tired after a busy day
# 来这儿吃一份甜的东西
They come and enjoy sweet foods
# 心情上 也会觉得很开心
And feel happy
# 来 走一个
Cheers
# 能看出来谁是领导了吗
Can you see who the boss is?
# 快吃吧 要不待会就会有很多人了
Eat faster, more people are coming
# 有没有发现 这是一家
Did you find out?
# 靠娘子军做起来的店
All workers are female
# 而且是一家只卖豆浆和油条的小吃店
And this restaurant only sell Youtiao and soy milk
# 所有的东西都是3块钱
Everything is 3 yuan each
# 即使是卖3块钱的东西
This restaurant is busy
# 店里也是很繁忙的
Even their food is only 3 yuan each
# 关 注 雪 鱼 探 店
Subscribe to XueYu